<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>com.cataclysmtlg.CataclysmTLG</id>
  <metadata_license>CC-BY-SA-3.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>CC-BY-SA-3.0</project_license>
  <name>Cataclysm: The Last Generation</name>
  <summary>
    A turn-based survival game set in a post-apocalyptic world
  </summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Struggle to survive in a harsh, persistent, procedurally
      generated world. Scavenge the remnants of a dead civilization
      for food, equipment, or, if you are lucky, a vehicle with a full
      tank of gas to get you the hell out of Dodge. Fight to defeat or
      escape from a wide variety of powerful monstrosities, from
      zombies to giant insects to killer robots and things far
      stranger and deadlier, and against the others like yourself,
      that want what you have...
    </p>
    <p>
      As your game begins, you awaken with hazy memories of violence
      and terror from when the world suddenly unraveled around
      you. Now you need to explore your surroundings, and secure food,
      water and safety. After that, who knows? Long term survival will
      mean tapping abilities you haven’t used before, learning to
      survive in this new environment and developing new skills.
    </p>
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
    <category>RolePlaying</category>
  </categories>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="violence-fantasy">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-bloodshed">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-desecration">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-slavery">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="violence-worship">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="drugs-alcohol">moderate</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="drugs-narcotics">moderate</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="drugs-tobacco">moderate</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-nudity">mild</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-themes">moderate</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-homosexuality">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="sex-appearance">mild</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-profanity">moderate</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-humor">mild</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="language-discrimination">mild</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <url type="homepage">
    https://github.com/Cataclysm-TLG/Cataclysm-TLG
  </url>
  <url type="bugtracker">
    https://github.com/Cataclysm-TLG/Cataclysm-TLG/issues
  </url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">
    https://github.com/Cataclysm-TLG/Cataclysm-TLG
  </url>
  <url type="contribute">
    https://github.com/Cataclysm-TLG/Cataclysm-TLG
  </url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.cataclysmtlg.CataclysmTLG.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <binary>cataclysm-tiles</binary>
  </provides>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.1 Beta" date="2024-12-08">
      <description>
        <p>
          The game is currently in beta. Pardon our dust as we work to
          clean up a host of bugs and implement the features that will
          differentiate us from our originating project, Cataclysm:
          Dark Days Ahead.
        </p>
        <p>
          The Last Generation is forked from a March 2024 build of Cataclysm:
          Dark Days Ahead, and has backported many of the changes that the
          originating project has made since then. TLG would not be possible
          without the past and present contributions of the hundreds of developers
          and contributors at Dark Days Ahead.
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Removed imgui for better performance and a cleaner, more classic appearance.</li>
          <li>Added a grappling system that greatly expands what is possible in combat.</li>
          <li>Rewrote lore to describe a Cataclysm spanning years, not weeks.</li>
          <li>Removed portal storms and Exodii, restoring bionics to labs and hospitals.</li>
          <li>Moved bionic professions to mainline, allowing players to start as cyborgs if desired.</li>
          <li>Overhauled item spawns at game start, making basic resources like food much more scarce.</li>
          <li>Adjusted plant/tree spawns according to real-world regional data.</li>
          <li>Killed a great number of wild plants to reflect a more apocalyptic setting.</li>
          <li>Farms generated at game start are poorly planted, afflicted by blight, and overrun by pests.</li>
          <li>Decreased the incidence of subway labs, increased the incidence of older-style labs.</li>
          <li>Reduced the number of monsters that spawn in subway labs.</li>
          <li>Reduced the number of inconsequential monsters that spawn in many areas to improve performance.</li>
          <li>Removed the ability of most creatures to become flesh cocoons on death, reducing amalgamation spam late-game.</li>
          <li>Made shooting non-deterministic, fixing an age-old issue with monsters being unerringly accurate.</li>
          <li>Overhauled acid and bile, which now behave as proper liquids and can interact with equipment.</li>
          <li>Re-added survivor suits and made them specialized for dealing with the above.</li>
          <li>Expanded weariness to more realistically model the effects of melee combat.</li>
          <li>Refactored much of the armor in the game for better balance, readability, and verisimilitude.</li>
          <li>Made unarmed combat far less destructive to the attacker's clothing.</li>
          <li>Tileset vehicle support for more cohesive vehicle rendering.</li>
          <li>Allowed Plant and Elf-A mutants to actually photosynthesize.</li>
          <li>Added some sanity to grenade behavior, making them less like nuclear bombs.</li>
          <li>Removed most item variants, simplifying loot and leaving more room for imagination.</li>
          <li>Made trapdoor spiders actually detectable.</li>
          <li>Implemented tempered glass for car windshields.</li>
          <li>Removed the two-drug system, simplifying mutagens. Now you just take a single drug to mutate.</li>
          <li>Made leap/pounce mutations actually functional.</li>
          <li>Improved point buy and made it the default character creation system. Freeform is still available.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
